Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
I see.
Then we have no other choice.
Are you certain you want to trust me?
We're ready anytime.
They got us here, too...
Captain!
He's recovering from his surgery fine. It's just overwork.
He needs some rest. Don't allow him to overwork himself again.
Right.
I'm worried about the Captain...
It'll be fine. He's immortal.
You're right.
Now we just need to find more water.
It'll work out.
You've changed.
That's it?
Yes.
The fourth planet in the Beemela system, Beemela-4.
Looks like it has plenty of water. There's oxygen, too.
As long as there's nothing dangerous down there, resupplying will be easy.
We might as well live there!
That's true.
Shima, prepare to land on Beemela-4.
Roger.
Kodai, form a landing party, and then take the lead.
Yes, sir.
Inputting landing coordinates. Latitude, North 37 degrees. Longitude, East 138 degrees.
No harmful chemicals in the atmosphere.
This is wonderful.
We'll be able to use this as a second Earth...
We've reached our position in the atmosphere.
Prepare to launch the Seagull.
Launching Seagull.
Seagull has launched.
The Yamato will hold position in atmosphere, at 1,500 meters,
and await report from the Seagull.
Misaki, are you not feeling well?
Airsick?
I-I'm all right!
It's just, lately, there have been times I can't remember.
That doesn't sound "all right" to me.
No, I'm okay!
Metal detected at one o'clock.
Let's have a look at it. Prepare for descent.
Niimi, you are a talented analyst.
And I respect you as one of my crew.
Thank you.
Is your plan for humanity to settle on Beemela-4?
For the Yamato to successfully complete its mission will be extremely difficult.
No, I'd go so far as to call it impossible.
We can continue warping, there isn't
enough time to make it to Iscandar and back.
And even if we reach the Large Magellanic Cloud, we don't know for sure where Iscandar is.
Correct?
But there's a possibility that Beemela could be a new home for all of us.
That's enough.
We should return to Earth and prepare to move humanity here.
I said enough.
Let's take this information to Earth.
Please, sir... Help me!
I cannot do that.
A splendid speech. But it seems
you've failed to win the XO's heart.
Your actions here almost amount to treason.
Security Officer, arrest Niimi.
Sorry, just doing my job.
Amazing... I didn't know you had that kind of equipment.
I am a superior unit, able to handle any mission.
Let's go, too.
Yeah.
You stay with the Seagull.
Yes, sir.
Hey, Misaki!
What's wrong? We'll leave you behind.
You're pretty awesome.
Analyzer, how far to that metal you were talking about?
Approximately three kilometers.
Someone... Someone is watching us.
What?
What? You apprehended the XO?
I didn't want to.
You're just going to go through with it?
We can't go back.
Make your decision, Shima...
What is it?
The XO is late.
That's true. He's usually very punctual.
What?!
What's happening?
U-Um, what's going on here?
Everyone, keep quiet.
Shima?
Ito, what are you doing?!
Do not use
under repairs
No luck here, either?
Attention all crew.
The Captain's illness has left him unable to fulfill his duties.
By his order, command of the ship is hereby transferred to Lieutenant Daisuke Shima.
What?!
Repeat, as of this moment,
Why are you here?
Command of the ship is hereby transferred to Lieutenant Daisuke Shima.
Are these all the pilots on standby?
I couldn't say... Maybe.
Yeah, he's right.
Hey, search for them.
Yes, sir.
No one was in the shower room.
This is Navigation Officer Shima.
I am temporarily in command of this ship.
Our investigation has revealed that the planet we're currently on,
Beemela-4, is suitable for human habitation.
At present, the Yamato is far behind schedule.
Thus, after discussion with the XO,
I have decided to suspend the Yamato Plan, which only offers a slim chance for
return before humanity's destruction.
Thus, we will return to Earth,
with information about this habitable planet.
What?!
As soon as we have resupplied, we'll leave Beemela-4.
This decision was made with Captain Okita's agreement, as well.
To avoid unnecessary confusion,
all crew is to obey the security staff.
What happened up there?
I don't know. Let's go talk to Shima and find out.
Right.
Yabu!
What are you doing?
I'm sorry...
We can't have you leaving now.
Amazing!
I hate bugs! I hate bugs!
Analyzer!
All right!
Misaki, are you all right?
Are you okay, Mr. Bug?
Mr. Bug? Mr. Bug?
Goodbye!
What happened?
We're saved.
Hey, Kodai...
Over there.
That's...
The engine room is under control, too.
The old men wield a lot of influence.
Good job, Navigation Officer.
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
This is treason.
Shut up.
Once we're back on Earth, I'll tell everyone—
I said shut up!
You want to go home that much, alien girl?
What are you talking about?!
Just what I said. She isn't from Earth.
Are you insane?
A year ago, didn't an Iscandarian bring us the Wave Motion Engine plans?
Yes, and all they told us was her name, not what became of her.
Yurisha Iscandar.
Now, where do you think she went?
I heard a rumor that she died in an accident.
But she's still alive...
And she's right here. She's been here the entire time.
I don't know what you're talking about.
That's...
Yes, it belongs to you.
But this isn't from Earth, is it?
Is it from this planet?
It looks like the Iscandarian ship I saw on Mars.
Of course it does. This is an Iscandarian ship.
No life signs detected.
Approximately four hundred years have passed since it crashed.
Was that big bug afraid of this?
A long, long time ago... Iscandar came.
Its task was salvation...
The salvation of all intelligent life in the universe.
That is the path of Iscandar, and the task of our family.
My beautiful Yurisha, my sister...
You will fulfill that task.
Bring hope to the people of Earth,
and the courage to make that hope reality.
And a trial, as well.
The salvation of all intelligent life in the universe.
That is the path of Iscandar...
Then you're saying there's intelligent life here?
There was.
There was a long time ago...
Misaki!
Are you okay?
Yes.
You're acting strangely.
Huh?
Oh, this hairstyle's weird, isn't it?
No, that isn't it.
Tactical Officer, I'm detecting another metallic signal up ahead.
Give us a trial, huh?
What does she think we are?
In the end, Iscandar is no different than Garmillas.
Misaki's intuition was right?
Huh? Uh...
Did I say something?
It seems that civilization on this planet has collapsed.
I estimate the time of its destruction as 330 years ago.
These are Beemelarians?
Probably so...
This looks like that big insect.
Most likely, a feral version of their livestock.
What's this?
This is a Wave Motion Core!
Navigation Officer, let's prepare to launch.
But Kodai and the others haven't...
I'd prefer to avoid unnecessary bloodshed.
You know what I'm trying to say, right?
We'll prepare to launch.
Doctor Sado?
Oh, it's Ito's little boy...
I'm closed for the day.
I need your help.
That's right, we can't reach the Yamato.
Same here. They aren't coming in.
What? Get ready to pick us up. Transmitting rendezvous point.
Tactical Officer?
There is some video data available.
Can you display it?
Yes.
What?
You will stay here until the ship's chain of command is reestablished.
I'm from Iscandar?
Don't worry about what Ito said.
Yamamoto! What are you doing here?
We should inform the landing party.
No, they've locked all communications down.
You're kidding.
There's one place.
One place we can communicate from.
Who's there?
It's Hoshina.
What do you want?
Out of the way! It's time for the Captain's checkup.
Doctor...
I was told to admit no one.
I have permission from Ito.
Tactical Officer, the Yamato...
Start an approach.
Seagull, can you hear me? This is the Yamato.
I see... I'd forgotten about this.
Seagull, come in. This is the Yamato.
This is the Seagull.
Kodai!
What do we do with the Captain and XO?
XO Sanada was murdered by a group that
desired to continue the journey to Iscandar.
And Okita will never recover from his ill—
What is it?
Ito, there's trouble!
Hangar 3 on the port side is opening!
What?
Stand by for guidance beacon.
What are you doing?
The landing party is back.
There's no need to allow them to board.
You're just going to leave them here?
Navigation Officer, please shut the hangar.
No more victims—
Navigation Officer!
I am in command here.
This is a problem... I have to insist.
I refuse.
That is unfortunate.
Ito!
It is very unfortunate.
No!
Let's put an end to this!
This is why I hate women!
Stop!
Hoshina...
You can't...
You fool!
Captain...
What are you doing?!
You betrayed me?
Not at all.
You were just on the wrong side.
There, there...
I won't let you pull any coup d'état while I'm around!
Kodai!
Mori?
I'm so glad you're safe, Kodai.
I'm so glad...
So you work for Director Todo, of Strategic Planning, Division 6?
Yes.
By his order, I was investigating the Izumo Plan backers that had infiltrated the Yamato.
I had no idea.
I couldn't prevent their mutiny from happening.
But it was thanks to Navigation Officer Shima
that I was able to prevent any bloodshed.
No, I'm responsible for this, as well.
One of the reasons this happened is
because we've fallen behind schedule.
There may be no further need for concern on that point.
If the information Kodai found on Beemela is accurate,
we can more than make up the lost time.
Really?
Yeah, if we hadn't stopped at Beemela, we would've never found it.
It's possible that all of this was a trial the Iscandarians set for us.
Crime and Punishment
Episode 16
A Choice for the Future
Crime and Punishment
No matter how steep or far the road is
I will not give up
Endless tears flowing down my cheek are not
A white flag of surrender
I go and become the wings of a loved one
Gather up the shattered dream
And take it to the end of the universe
Steady as she goes!
Row strongly
And hold your thoughts close to your chest
Steady as she goes!
Through your despair
A ray of light shines
The ancient gate:
a bridge between the stars that hangs suspended in the void.
Kodai and his team infiltrate a control satellite to activate the gate.
There, they hear a story of the past,
and the door to that time will now be opened.
Next time: Out of the Forest of Memory.
There are 275 days left before humanity is extinct.